# **Charles Henry Armentrout V**

www.linkedin.com/in/charmentroutv www.github.com/LegNBass charmentroutv@gmail.com

**Present Address** 5973 Dixon Dr. Raleigh, NC 27609 (336) 681-7224

Permanent Address 114 East Keeling Rd Greensboro, NC 27410

#### **Career Profile**

Passionate, lead software engineer who undertakes complex projects utilizing knowledge of Python, Docker, Bash, JavaScript, etc. Possesses practical experience in server-less architectures. Has experience with database administration and schema design, as well as application containerization and horizontal scaling applications. Also possesses strong interpersonal skills for successful team work and collaboration.

## **Professional Experience**

Software Team Lead, The McClatchy Company, Raleigh NC

Feb 2020-Present

- · Manage and lead a team of remote engineers
- Architecht and implement solutions for enterprise ETL processing
- Python, AWS (Lambda, Glue, S3, RDS, DynamoDB, etc), SQL

## Senior Automation Architect, Credit Suisse, Durham, NC

Nov 2019-Feb 2020

- Design and implement automation solutions for security response workflows.
- Python

## Senior Software Engineer, Cisco Systems, Durham, NC

Jan 2017-Nov 2019

- Architect database schema for web application backend
- · Architect and implement REST API for web-to-backend communication in Flask
- Design and implement Network Devices testing platform in python
- Automate deployment of multiple applications with Docker and Docker-Compose
- Debug and Maintain Kubernetes-based application infrastructure
- · Python (Flask, SQLAlchemy, etc), Docker, SQL, Robot, TextFSM, Linux

## Software Engineer, Deloitte, Morrisville, NC

Jul 2014-Jan 2017

- · Lead maintenance of legacy system.
- Implement infrastructure and orchestration of API based parallel service container platform using Docker, Apache Zookeeper, NGINX, Vagrant, and Cassandra DB.
- Develop and maintain full-stack web-facing applications utilizing a python backend.
- · Python (Flask, NumPy, Pandas, etc), Docker, Linux

### Software Developer, ICF International, Martinsville, VA

Dec 2013-Jul 2014

- · Integrate applications with MS SQL Server, SharePoint, and other services
- Create custom web forms using JavaScript, HTML5, and ASP .NET with C#
- Design database schema to support projects and applications
- Automate previously manual reporting processes
- C# (ASP .NET), SQL, PowerShell

Analyst, Supplemental Software Solutions, Greensboro, NC

Sep 2012-Dec 2013

#### Education

# Appalachian State University, Boone, NC

May 2012

- B.S. Finance and Banking
- B.S. Risk Management and Insurance

### Computer Skills

Languages: Python, Go, Bash, JavaScript, HTML5, Haskell, C#, VBA Script, Batch, Perl, SQL,

CQL, LATEX

Frameworks/Systems: Flask, Docker, Docker-Compose, K8s, AWS (S3, Lambda, EC2, Glue,

Cloudformation, Cloudwatch), Git, Ansible, Jenkins, NGINX